Talking just causes witnesses.
Winter's Bone is a drama, mystery film directed by Debra Granik.
After discovering her father put their house up for his bail bond and then disappeared, 17-year-old Ree Dolly must confront the
local criminal underworld and the harsh Ozark wilderness in order to to track down her father and save her family.
Ree Dolly, played by Jennifer Lawrence.
Teardrop, played by John Hawkes.
Little Arthur, played by Kevin Breznahan.
Merab, played by Dale Dickey.
Sheriff Baskin, played by Garret Dillahunt.
April, played by Sheryl Lee.
Winter's Bone is a 2010 American coming-of-age
tragedy film directed by Debra Granik.
It was adapted by Granik and Anne Rosellini from
the 2006 novel by Daniel Woodrell.
The film stars Jennifer Lawrence as a poverty-stricken teenage girl named Ree Dolly in the rural Ozarks
of Missouri who must locate her missing father to save her family from homelessness.
Winter's Bone received critical acclaim upon release, with high
praise directed towards Lawrence's performance.
The film also emerged as a commercial success at the box-office,
earning $16.1 million on a budget of $2 million.
The film won several awards, including the Grand Jury Prize:
Dramatic Film at the 2010 Sundance Film Festival.
It received four Oscar nominations at the 83rd Academy Awards: Best Picture, Best Adapted Screenplay, Best Actress in a Leading Role for
Lawrence (who at 20 was the second-youngest Best Actress nominee at the time), and Best Supporting Actor for John Hawkes.
In addition, Lawrence was nominated for Best Actress – Motion Picture Drama and Outstanding Leading
Actress at the 68th Golden Globe Awards and 17th Screen Actors Guild Awards, respectively.
The film explores themes of sheriff, based on novel or
book, missouri, suspicion, teenage girl.
The tone is emotional and mind_bending.